Mss.497.3.H35o
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 15, 1818; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.215-218.) Concerning Indian languages. Concerning certain Indian customs.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 18, 1818; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.219-222.) Concerning Indian languages. Concerning his publication. Refers to the Historical committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 22, 1818; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.223-226.) Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 25, 1818; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p. and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.227-230.) Concerning his publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Oct. 29, 1818; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.233-234.) Concerning his publication. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1818; 11x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.239-242.) Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Nov. 8, 1818; 11-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.243-246.) Concerning his publication. Deposits the Zeisberger items with the APS.from the Moravian archives.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Nov. 25, 1818; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp. 247-250.) Concerning Indian publications forthcoming from the Committee. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Dec. 5, 1818; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp. 251-254.) Concerning Indian languages. Refers to Gambold. Concerning publications of the APS Historical and Literary committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Dec. 26, 1818; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p. and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.255-258.) Concerning his publication. Refers to Dencke. Asks of Boudinot.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Jan. 31, 1819; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp. 259-262.) Concerning Indian languages. Friendly letter. Refers to Dencke.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Feb. 3, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.263-266.) Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Feb. 7, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.267-270.) Concerning the study of Indian languages by the committee. Refers to Zeisberger, Barton and Dencke.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 14, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.271-274.) Concerning his publication. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 21, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.275-278.) Concerning Dencke and Indian translation. Refers to Barton and botany. the APS, Wistar and Jefferson. Concerning his publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 29, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.279-282.) Concerning comments on his publication. Does not think he can write more of Indian languages. Refers to the Historical committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, April 8, 1819; 10-3/4x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.283-286.) Concerning a translation into Indian languages. Refers to Zeisberger, the Historical committee, and sends part of a letter from Dencke. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc.Collections, Ser.2,vol.9,xxvii-xxviii.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 21, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.287-290.) Thanks of the Moravians for the publication of the Historical committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 29, 1819; 11x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.291-294.) Concerning Indian linguistics. Friendly letter. Concerning the distribution of his publication. Refers to Zeisberger and Dencke.and the committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, May 15, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.295-298.) Concerning the distribution of his publication. Concerning Dencke and his writing on Indian languages. Refers to Correa de Serra and the committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, May 30, 1819; 11-3/4x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.299-302.) Concerning his writings on Indian languages and histories. Refers to Humboldt, the committee, Wistar, Dencke and Barton.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, July 1, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder, Letters...; pp.303-306) Concerning his publication. Concerning Indian history. Refers to Adams and Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, July 10, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.307-310.) Concerning the Indians and their languages. Refers to the committee. Copies extract of a letter from Abraham Steiner.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, July 18, 1819; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.311-314.) Concerning his publication. Concerning Vater.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, July 25, 1819; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In German. (see Heckwelder. Letters...; pp.315-318.) His publications, foreign scholars. Mentions Vater, Bartram, Barton. Indian language.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Aug. 15, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.319-322.) Concerning Indian linguistics. Refers to Adelung, C.W.Peale, Peale's museum, Vaux and Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Sept. 18, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.323-326.) Concerning a review of his work. Concerning the Indians, their languages and further work on them. Refers to Vaux.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Sept. 25, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp. 327-330.) Is sorry his eyes are bad. Concerning Indian words.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 10, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.331-334.) Concerning reviews of his publication. Refers to Vater. Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Nov. 17, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.335-338.) Concerning Indian languages. Is placing accent marks on various publications to be sent to Europe.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.339-342.) Forwards books in Indian languages. Anecdote on difficulty in writing an Indian tongue. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Dec. 5, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.343-346.) Concerning a publication for Vater on Indians. Concerning a sketch of Indians which Peale might copy. Refers to John Vaughan.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Dec. 15, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, L.S. 2p.and add;end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.347-350.) Concerning his publication. Refers to Albers, the committee, and John Vaughan.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Jan. 8, 1820; 13x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.351-352.) Concerning Indians. Refers to his new publications and to Vaux.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Feb. 19, 1820; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.353-356.) Concerning the Indians and their languages. Refers to J.Vaughan, the APS, Vaux, Mrs. Logan, C.Thomson, Zeisberger, and his new publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 4, 1820; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.357-360.) Forwards manuscript dictionaries of Indian languages. Refers to Vaughan and Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 19, 1820; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.361-364.) Concerning Indian linguistics. Forwards books to J. Vaughan. Asks what T. Jefferson thought of his publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 31, 1820; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.365-368.) Concerning publications on Indians and their languages. Refers to Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 20, 1820; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.369-372.) Concerning his forthcoming publication. Refers to Vaux.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, May 16, 1820; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.373-376.) Concerning his publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, June 11, 1820; 9-3/4x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.377-380.) Concerning his publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, July 15, 1820; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.381-384.) Concerning Indian languages. Refers to the committee. Forwards copies of his Narrative to him and the APS.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Aug. 2, 1820; 9-3/4x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.385-388.) Concerning Indian languages of the U.S.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Aug. 18, 1820; 10x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.389-392.) Concerning publications on the Indians and their languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 7, 1820; 9-3/4x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.393-396.) Concerning Indian languages. Will send copy of his Narrative for the APS.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Jan. 11, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.397-400.) Concerning the Indians of the U.S. Will send his Narrative of the APS.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Jan. 15, 1821; 8x4-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.401-404.) Forwards Narrative for the APS and encloses list of errata. Concerning Indian words.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 31, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.405-408.) Forwards publications for himself and the committee. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, June 16, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.409-412.) Death of Albers. Friendly letter. Refers to Mitchill.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, July 14, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.413-416.) Concerning the possibility of his Account being printed in England. Refers to Zeisberger, Humboldt and the APS Concerning Indian Vocabularies.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Aug. 7, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.417-420.) Concerning Indian languages. Sends Zeisberger book for the APS or Humboldt. Refers to Jefferson and Mitchill.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.421-424.) Concerning Indian languages. Printed: Coll.Mass.Hist.Soc.Ser.2,vol. 9,xv-xvi note. DuPonceau. "Notes..."
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Aug. 25, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckwelder. Letters...; pp.425-428.) Concerning Indian languages. Refers to Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Sept. 13, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.429-432.) Concerning Indian languages. Does not believe Dencke can be relied on to draw up an Indian vocabulary.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 9, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.433-436.) Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Oct. 11, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.437-438.) Concerning Indian numerals.
  - Letter to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 13, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.439-442.) Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc.,Collections, Ser.2,Vol.9,xxxvi-x1. On same sheet is letter from DuPonceau to Pickering; Oct. 16, 1821.
  - Letter to John Pickering, Salem, Oct. 16, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; p.441.) Forwards letter from Heckewelder. On same sheet as letter from Heckewelder to DuPonceau; Oct. 13, 1821.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 18, 1821; 10-3/4x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end.with forwarding note from DuPonceau to John Pickering. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.443-446.) Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Oct. 25, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.447-448. ) Concerning Indian languages. Refers to Pickering.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Feb. 28, 1822; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.449-452.) Concerning his Narrative. Forwards list of Indian names for the committee.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 19, 1822; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.453-456.) Concerning Indian affairs. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 23, 1822; 10x7-1/2; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.457-460.) Thanks for German translation of his Account. Refers to Schweinitz and the APS.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 28, 1822; 9-3/4x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.461-464. ) Concerning his Narrative. Concerning Indians.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, May 5, 1822; 9-3/4x8; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Heckewelder. Letters...; pp.465-468.) Concerning publications on Indians. Refers to Pickering and Schweinitz. Refers to the APS.